Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
- Collections of Framed Items
  - Portraits of a man and a woman, 1852; BANC PIC 1982.101:01-02--FR; 2 drawings on paper: charcoal; visible image 36 x 27 cm
    - [Portrait of a man], 1852; Fenderich, Charles; BANC PIC 1982.101:01--FR; 1 drawing: charcoal and white chalk; visible image 35.2 x 26.7 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): Ch. Fenderich / 1852.
      Portraits; Charcoal drawings
    - [Portrait of a woman], 1852; Fenderich, Charles; BANC PIC 1982.101:02--FR; 1 drawing: charcoal and white chalk; 35.7 x 26.2 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): Ch. Fenderich / 1852.
  - Two views of the vessel City of Rio de Janeiro, [not before 1901?]; BANC PIC 1984.048:01-02--FR
    - The Shipping Vessel "The City of Rio de Janeiro" in Calm, [not before 1901?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1984.048:01--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on academy board: oil; visible image 43.7 x 57.7 cm. On bow of ship: City of Rio de Janeiro. On mast flag: MSU. On verso: looks like "City of Rio de Janeiro" on bow. The artist who made / the S in MSU on flag / made it backwards / RBH / 1962.
      Steamship with bow at right in calm waters with US flag at stern. Bermuda(?) flag on foremast. The merchant vessel sank with 146 passengers aboard in the waters of the Golden Gate strait, California, in 1901.
      Vessels; Marines (Visual works); City of Rio de Janeiro (Steamship) -- Pictorial works; Steamboats -- Pictorial works
    - The Shipping Vessel "The City of Rio de Janeiro" in Storm, [not before 1901?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1984.048:02--FR; 1 painting on canvas on academy board: oil; visible image 43.4 x 57.8 cm. Painted on bow of ship: City of Rio de Janeiro.
      Steamship in rough seas. The merchant vessel sank with 146 passengers aboard in the waters of the Golden Gate strait, California, in 1901.
  - Portraits of California Indians, a Klamath and the Doctor, ca. 1860; BANC PIC 1984.100:01-02--FR; 2 photographic prints: albumen; visible image 20 x 13 cm
    - A Klamath, "The White Deer Skin" dressed for a dance, [ca. 1860]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1984.100:01--FR; 1 photograph mounted on paper: albumen; image 12.3 x 8.5 cm on paper, visible image 20.9 x 13.2 cm Handwritten (LC) A Klamath: / "The White=deer=skin"; dressed / for a dance; (LL): inserted by B M.
      Half length portrait of Indian woman wearing a woven skull cap and a deer skin cloak.
      Albumen prints; Klamath Indians -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- California -- Portraits; Indians of North America -- California -- Costume and adornment -- Pictorial works
    - "The Doctor" or J. Tavleera, Crescent City, Del Norte County, California, [ca. 1860]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1984.100:02--FR; 1 photograph mounted on paper: albumen; image 11.7 x7.7 cm on paper, visible image 20.8 x 13.3 cm. Handwritten (LC): "The Doctor" - / - Tavleera, Crescent City, / Del Norte County; California; (LL): inserted by B M.
      Half length standing portrait of elderly Native American man wearing woven skull cap, beaded necklaces and animal pelts standing behind ivy covered balustrade (studio prop).
  - Items from: Douglas Tilden pictorial collection, ca. 1860-ca. 1979; BANC PIC 1989.037
    - [Joseph and Mary in Bethlehem], [19--?]; McNaughton, J.; BANC PIC 1989.037:001--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 23.8 x 18.3 cm. Painted signature (LL): J McNaughton. Painted (LL): A Mon Amis Tilden.
      Nocturnal scene of a narrow street in a middle eastern city showing a man and donkey near a doorway where a woman, possibly carrying a baby, is standing.
    - [Portrait of a Mediterranean woman], 1892; Varveris, N.; BANC PIC 1989.037:002--FR; 1 painting on academy board: oil; visible image 23.5 x 28.4 cm. Signature and date (LR): N Varveris / Paris 1892. Painted (LL): A mon ami Tilden. Handwritten (verso): French figure. Label (verso of panel) Couleurs & Vernis / Sales / 21 bis Bould. Montparnasse / Papeterie Registres.
      Half length portrait of woman in ethnic costume (French or Greek possibly) with a white, wide sleeved chemise; gold-rimmed waistcoat; red beret with tassel; and gold bracelets.
    - [Marinescape], 1892; Walden, Lionel; BANC PIC 1989.037:003--FR; 1 painting: oil; 30.7 x 44.9 cm. Handwritten (LL): A mon ami / Tilden / Paris '92 / [signed] Lionel Walden. Numerous labels and biographical information about artist on verso of frame.
      Sailboats moored in quiet, sunlit bay.
      Oil paintings; Marines (Visual works)
    - [Ships in Harbor], [189-?]; Walden, Lionel; BANC PIC 1989.037:004--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 19.6 x 28.8 cm. Handwritten (LR): A mon ami / Tilden / [signed] Lionel Walden. Label (on verso of frame) from Bowinkel's Art Store, Los Angeles, CA.
      Bay with numerous boats on water.
  - Prints from the Roger Levenson papers, ca. 1820-ca. 1890; BANC PIC 1994.045--FR; 2 prints: hand colored etching and photogravure; 35 x 25 cm. and 15 x 11 cm.
    - The Man Wots Got the Whip Hand of 'Em All, 1820; Heath, William; McLean, T. (Thomas); BANC PIC 1994.045:01--FR; 1 print: engraving, hand-colored; visible image 37.7 x 28.1 cm. Printed (LR): Pub May 30th 1820 by T. McLean 26 Haymarket Sole Publisher of PPry caricatures.
      Caricature of Free Press; fire breathing printing press with legs, wearing liberty cap and laurel wreath.
      Cartoons (Commentary); Etchings; Printing presses -- Pictorial works; Freedom of the press -- Europe -- Caricatures and cartoons; Printers -- Caricatures and cartoons
    - John Baskerville, [ca. 1890?]; Walker, Emery, Sir; BANC PIC 1994.045:02--FR; 1 print: photogravure; visible image 15.6 x 11.7 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): From a picture after Miller in the national Portrait Gallery, London; (LR): Emery Walker Ph. sc. Handwritten (LL in window below image): With the compliments of / DB Updike. Provenance information handwritten (on verso).
      Photogravures; Printers -- Portraits; Baskerville, John, -- 1706-1775 -- Portraits
  - California lithographs from the collection of Paul H. Mawdsley, between 1850 and 1900; BANC PIC 1998.010--FR; 5 prints: lithograph, hand colored and chromolithographs; various sizes
    - Bridal Veil Fall, Yosemite, [between 1850 and 1875]; Gemmell, J. (firm); BANC PIC 1998.010:01--FR; 1 print: lithograph, hand-colored; visible image 29.2 x 36.6 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): Lith. & Published by J. Gemmell; (LR): 123 Randolf St. Cor. of Clark, Chicago.
      A distant view of fall with Indian encampment in foreground showing a Teepee, a woman with child, and adolescent and three adult males with weapons.
      Lithographs -- Hand-colored; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - American District Telegraph, [between 1880 and 1900]; Schmidt Label & Lith. Co.; BANC PIC 1998.010:02--FR; 1 print: chromolithograph; visible image 52.4 x 34.3 cm. Printed title (UC in image). Printed (LL): Schmidt Label and Lith. Co., S.F.
      Five part image showing telegraph messengers and office in center with marginal images showing a burglary, sickbed, fire, and residences.
      Lithographs; American District Telegraph Company -- Pictorial works
    - Spruance Stanley & Co., Wines & liquors, San Francisco, [between 1870 and 1900]; Bühler, F.; F. Korbel & Bros.; BANC PIC 1998.010:03--FR; 1 print: lithograph, color; visible image 47.8 x 63.2 cm. Printed title (UC). Printed (LR): F. Bühler; (LC): Lith. F. Korbel & Bros. S.F.
      Promotional poster for wine and liquor importer and dealer based in San Francisco. Central image of women bathers surrounded by marginal images of the store front, storehouse, distillery, wares, and cherubs reaping wheat and drinking.
      Lithographs -- Color; Advertisements -- California; Spruance Stanley & Co. -- Pictorial works
    - The California Powder Works, Santa Cruz County, California, [between 1875 and 1900]; Bosqui Eng. & Ptg. Co.; BANC PIC 1998.010:04--FR; 1 print: lithograph, color; visible image 51.3 x 66.2 cm. Printed title (LC); (LR): Bosqui Eng. Co. S.F.
      Elevated view of powder works including industrial buildings, factory, and warehouses situated along one side of river surrounded by heavily wooded mountains; elevated waterway in center.
      Lithographs -- Color; California Powder Works -- Pictorial works
    - Home Mutual Insurance Company of California, [between 1874 and 1900]; Bosqui Eng. & Ptg. Co.; BANC PIC 1998.010:05--FR; 1 print: lithograph, color; visible image 53.5 x 67.7 cm. Printed title (UC and LC). Printed (LR): The Bosqui Eng. & Print. Co. S.F.
      Image of underwriters fire patrol (firefighters and horsedrawn fire wagon) rushing past U.S. Mint (San Francisco, Calif.) chased by dogs. Image surrounded by Heraldic Regalia.
      Lithographs -- Color; Advertisements -- California; Home Mutual Insurance Company of California -- Pictorial works
  - The Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Works in Kalihi, Honolulu and in Berkeley, California, ca. 1897 and 1905; BANC PIC 1998.068--FR; 2 drawings: sepia wash and ink; visible images 36 x 52 cm. and 39 x 54 cm
    - [The Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Co., Berkeley, CA, at Second and Hearst], [ca. 1897]; Burgess, George Henry; BANC PIC 1998.068:1--FR; 1 drawing: sepia wash and ink heightened in white; visible image 35.7 x 51.7 cm. Title ( in image on building): The Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Co.
      View of busy wharf-side, industrial operation showing office and laboratory buildings, warehouses and transporation such as trains, horse drawn wagons, and ships. San Francisco Bay visible in the distance.
      Drawings; Wash drawings; Guano industry -- California -- Berkeley -- Pictorial works; Factories -- California -- Berkeley -- Pictorial works; Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Works -- Pictorial works; Fertilizer industry -- California -- Berkeley -- Pictorial works
    - [The Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Co., Kalihi, HI], [1905]; Burgess, George Henry; BANC PIC 1998.068:2--FR; 1 drawing: sepia wash and ink heightened in white; visible image 39.2 x 54.2 cm. Title (in image, LR): Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Co., ...Kalihi, Honolulu, T.H.
      View of industrial operation in tropical setting, showing numerous buildings and warehouses with trains and horse drawn wagons. Trolley car in foreground.
      Wash drawings; Pacific Guano and Fertilizer Works -- Pictorial works; Fertilizer industry -- Hawaii -- Pictorial works; Guano industry -- Hawaii -- Pictorial works; Factories -- Hawaii -- Pictorial works
  - Items from: The mission era: California under Spain and Mexico and The mission era [graphic]: California under Spain and Mexico and reminiscences, ca. 1850-1878; BANC PIC 19xx.039
    - Ex-Mission (now Parish-Church) of San Gabriel, 1878; Vischer, Edward; BANC PIC 19xx.039:09--FR; 1 painting: watercolor and pencil on paper; 15.2 x 21.6 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): E. Vischer, 1878. Handwritten title (LC). Handwritten (lower margin): after Hahn's celebrated picture in the possession of M. Sherwood. Original by C. Hahn. In appreciation of the merits of the original, and in friendly remembrance of its genial author, with his permission reproduced by E. Vischer, 1878. Sunday-gatherings after Mass.
      Sunday gathering after mass outside church showing vaqueros on horseback, women and children. Based on an original by C. Hahn.
      Watercolors; San Gabriel Mission (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - A California magnate in his home, 1865; Vischer, Edward; BANC PIC 19xx.039:33--FR; 1 painting: watercolor and pencil on paper; 14.7 x 20.7 cm. Handwritten title (LC). Handwritten (lower margin): General Don Andres Pico of Los Angeles, 1865. Southern mission orchard; vaqueros lassoing cattle; corridor of the farm-building. Ex-Mission of San Fernando.
      Image of General Don Andres Pico (1810-1876) of Los Angeles, 1865, showing corridor of farm building (ex-mission of San Fernando) with men, women, children, and animals in foreground. Includes the southern mission orchard and vaqueros lassoing cattle in distance.
      Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; Watercolors; Missions; Pencil works; Californios; Generals--Mexico
  - [Portraits of Emperor Maximilian and Empress Carlotta of Mexico], 186-; BANC PIC 19xx.323; 2 paintings: oil on panel
    - [Portrait of Empress Carlotta of Mexico], [186-]; Unknown; BANC PIC 19xx.323:1--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on panel: oil; visible image 43.5 x 35.8 cm.
      Bust length portrait of Empress Carlota (1840-1927) in plain black dress; a companion piece to Maximilian of Mexico. Born Marie-Charlotte-Amelie-Augustine-Victoire-Clementine-Leopoldine on May 7, 1840 in Laeken, Belgium. She was the daughter of King Leopold I of Belgium and Louise Marie d' Orleans, eldest daughter of King Louis Philippe of France. After suffering from mental illness following her husband's death in 1867, she died January 1, 1927 near Brussels.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Carlota, -- Empress, consort of Maximilian, Emperor of Mexico, -- 1840-1927
    - [Portrait of Emperor Maximilian of Mexico], [186-]; Unknown; BANC PIC 19xx.323:2--FR; 1 painting on panel: oil; visible image 43.5 x 35.8 cm.
      Bust portrait of Ferdinand Maximilian Joseph, Archdukle of Austria, wearing plain black suit with a gold medal (cross emblem) and small round brooch. In 1864, following the French occupation of Mexico City, Maximllian of Austria was named emporer of Mexico. He was shot in 1867 after Mexican forces regained control of the country.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Maximilian, -- Emperor of Mexico, -- 1832-1867 -- Portraits
  - Framed artwork miscellany, BANC PIC 19xx.500--FR
    - Men of Mark, c1895; Taber, I. W. (Isaiah West); Bourke, J.F.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:001--FR; 1 photograph: albumen; 42.5 x 49.6 cm. Printed title and date (C). Printed (LL): Copyright 1895, J. F. Bourke; (LR): Taber photographer.
      Composite group portrait consisting of busts of prominent men. Numbered legend below image corresponding to portraits with names and occupations of sitters.
    - [Robert Louis Stevenson], 1897; Breuer, Henry Joseph; BANC PIC 19xx.500:002--FR; 1 image on wood: incised; 48 x 61 cm. Carved signature and date (UR): H. J. Breuer 1897. Carved inscription (LC): A spirit goes out of the / man who means execution, / which outlives the most / untimely ending / -Æs Triplex.
    - [River mill in mountain landscape], [1885]; Briggs, A. L. (Lawrence?); BANC PIC 19xx.500:003--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 49.7 x 90.2 cm. Painted signature (LR): A.L. Briggs. Source of date is unknown. University of California label on verso (78-10-06365).
      Autumn landscape with small mill building and waterwheel along river bank, and rolling hills in distance.
    - [Fox], [before 1892]; Brooks, Samuel Marsden; BANC PIC 19xx.500:004--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 76.6 x 62.6 cm. Painted signature (LL): S. M. Brookes. University California label (78-10-06364) on verso.
    - [Portrait of Darius Ogden Mills], 1887; Keith, William; BANC PIC 19xx.500:047--FR; 1 painting on canvas: oil; 75 x 62.5 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): W. Keith / S.F. / 1887.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Mills, Darius Ogden, 1825-1910 -- Portraits
    - [Swag of Grapes], [18--]; Brooks, Samuel Marsden; BANC PIC 19xx.500:005--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 60.2 x 50.4 cm. Painted signature (LL): Brookes. UC inventory label (verso): 78-10-06363.
      Bunch of grapes hanging on a white brick wall.
    - [Adobe Ruins], [19--?]; Cross, Lee H.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:006--FR; 1 painting: oil; 40.7 x 50.8 cm. Painted signature (LL): L. H. Cross.
      Shell of adobe building surrounded by trees.
    - The Golden Gate, San Francisco Bay, 1878 (c1881); Davidson, J.O.; Beckwite, H. S.; William Pate & Company; BANC PIC 19xx.500:007--FR; 1 print: steel engraving; visible image 53.4 x 72.5 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed signature (LR in image): J. O. Davidson / Fordham, 1878. Printed (LL): Painted by J. O. Davidson; (LC): Entered according to act of Congress A.D. 1881 by W. M. Pate & Co. [...]; (LC below title): William Pate & Company, New York & London.; (LR): Engraved by H. S. Beckwite.
      Ships on rough waters including a two masted schooner, several sailboats, a steamship, and tugboats on the bay. Marin headlands in left distance, city in right.
    - [Mine Inn: Tudor Building in Forest], [before 1923]; Deakin, Edwin; BANC PIC 19xx.500:008--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 75 x 49.7 cm. Painted signature (LR): Edwin Deakin. Title from sign on upper gable (in image): Mine Inn by E. Deakin. UC inventory label (verso): 78-10-06128.
      Tudor building with various gables. The sign over the door reads "We Three Logger Heads Be" which is a reference to the two figures in the sign and the spectator, a figure with a sketchbook(?) who stands in front of the building. A small sign on the upper gable reads "Mine Inn by E. Deakin."
    - [View of San Francisco harbor and Dollar steamship], [194-?]; Dollar Steamship Lines; BANC PIC 19xx.500:009--FR; 1 photograph: hand colored; visible image 59.8 x 100.2 cm.
      Waterfront area with yacht club or restaurant in foreground and pier with two steamships dockside (one with dollar sign on stack). Cars, horsedrawn buggies and pedestrians on street.
    - [Doorway to House], [19--?]; H.S.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:012--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 20.7 x 13.9 cm. Handwritten initials (LR): H. S.
      Quaint view of cottage entryway with small brick pillars and wall surrounding steps leading to arched doorway.
      Watercolors; Dwellings
    - [Portrait of an unidentified man], [ca. 1880-ca. 1900]; Lainer, (Charles?); BANC PIC 19xx.500:013--FR; 1 photograph: hand colored; visible image 66 x 53.3 cm. Handwritten signature (LL): Lainer.
    - [Portrait of John Muir], [19--?]; Muir, David; BANC PIC 19xx.500:014--FR; 1 drawing: charcoal; 60.5 x 44.5 cm. Letter with provenance information (filed in INV) attributes drawing to David Muir, brother of John Muir.
      Bust length portrait of young John Muir.
      Portraits; Drawings
    - [Locomotive Design], 1860; Oliver, William Letts; BANC PIC 19xx.500:015--FR; 1 drawing: watercolor and ink; visible image 39 x 49.5 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LR): William Oliver 1860. UC label (78-10-06278).
      Profile view of locomotive.
      Watercolors; Locomotives -- Pictorial Works
    - Alsace, 1914; Prud'homme, G.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:016--FR; 1 image on bronze: sculptural relief; 27.2 x 20.5 cm. Sculpted signature and date (LR): G. Prud'homme 1914. Sculpted title (UL).
      Profile bust-length portrait of young woman.
    - What Am I Bid for this Fine Pair of Pants!, 1971; Renault, Dennis; BANC PIC 19xx.500:017--FR; 1 drawing: ink; visible image 32.3 x 26.8 cm. Handwritten signature and date (LL): Renault (circa 11-71). Handwritten title: (LC). Handwritten (UL running vertically): For Roger Levenson, friend and mentor from/ Dennis / Renault / 6/28/85.
      Satirical image of Governor Reagan as auctioneer preparing to sell rare University of California library books. Cartoon appeared in the Sacramento Bee November 10, 1971 (Vol. 229-number 37552).
    - [Lt. George H. Derby], [185-?]; Rufalin, H.M.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:018--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 90.7 x 72.3 cm. Engraved plaque (LC of frame): General John J. Sutter / 1803-1880 / California pioneer. Typed label (LC of frame over plaque): Probably / Lt. Geo. H. Derby, U.S.A. / cf. F855.1 D427P vol. 1X / frontispiece. Handwritten (verso of stretcher): presented to Dr. C. M. Hitchcock / by the unfortunate subject G.H.D. / "This IS a Rose." Handwritten (verso of frame): [H?]. M. Rufalin. Inventory stamp (verso): Oct. 1951 (#276).
      Half length portrait of George Horatio Derby (1823-1861) in military uniform with a bay [of San Francisco?] visible in distance. Derby served as a lieutenant in California from 1853-1856 and was a western humorist who wrote under the pseudonyms John Phoenix and John P. Squibob.
    - [Mission Dolores?], [ca. 1915]; Ruiz, B. Yamero; BANC PIC 19xx.500:019--FR; 1 painting on canvas: oil; visible image 12.2 x 20.8 cm. Handwritten (verso): A gift from the artist Ruiz - to Raphael [Bennet?] - about 1915 / He stated it was the Mission Dolores - however I cannot see anything familiar about this view - or from this angle. (not signed); (UL): B.Y. Ruiz / Home: San Jose, Calif. / studio sometimes in S.F.
      Mission building façade, purportedly Mission Dolores, also known as San Francisco de Asis Mission established in 1776. [Could this be Mission San Francisco Solano, Sonoma, Calif., and not Mission Dolores in San Francisco, Calif.?]
      Oil paintings; San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Missions; Buildings
    - Bret Harte, [ca. 1878?]; Schneider, R.F. (attr. to); BANC PIC 19xx.500:020--FR; 1 painting: oil on canvas; visible oval image 16.6 x 12.8 cm. Plaque on frame (LC): Bret Harte. Label (verso): R. F. Schneider / Crefeld Ostwall 25. Handwritten on label (verso, UL): Bret Harte. Handwritten (verso): Thought to be by / R. F. Schneider / Crefeld, Germany / painted when B. H. / was US Consul / there / J [E?] 11/12/73.
      Bust-length portrait of Harte (1836-1902).
    - [Seascape at sunset], [19--]; Sears, Benjamin Willard; BANC PIC 19xx.500:021--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 24.3 x 34.6 cm. Painted signature (LR): Sears. Inventory stamp (verso): Oct. 1951. UC inventory label (verso, LL): 78-10-06278.
      Coastal scene showing rocky beach and setting sun, with ships in the distance.
    - [Cityscape of San Francisco]: The Vacant Court, [ca. 1930]; Short-Jackson, Jessie Francis; BANC PIC 19xx.500:022--FR; 1 drawing: pastel; visible image 34.5 x 53.5 cm. Handwritten (verso): The Vacant Court. Label on verso from the Golden Gate International Exposition (GGIE).
      Urban view of street intersection on hill looking towards back of buildings with San Francisco City Hall in distance. Several figures on sidewalk.
    - Frank Norris After a Study by Arnold Genthe, 1918; Sweigert; BANC PIC 19xx.500:023--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 29 x 39.3 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): Sweigert / Delta Xi '18. Handwritten title (verso): Frank Norris / After a study by / Arnold Genthe.
      Bust-length portrait of California novelist Frank Norris (1870-1902) with a pig and owl holding a knife and fork above his shoulder; probably a reference to his undergraduate days as a member of Phi Gamma Delta, Delta Xi Chapter, University of California at Berkeley where he founded "pig dinner."
    - [Some Ships of the U.S. Pacific Squadron], [18--]; Toler, William Pinkley; BANC PIC 19xx.500:027--FR; 1 drawing: pencil; visible image 25 x 50.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LL): W. P. Toler. Descriptive label on verso.
      View of five masted ships on the water including (left to right) the United States, Savannah, Columbus, Dale or Cyane, and the Portsmouth.
      Formerly ff F591.T6 x.
      Drawings; United States -- Navy. -- Pacific fleet -- History
    - [Cityscape with Children], 1880; Williams, Virgil; BANC PIC 19xx.500:028--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 74.3 x 36.1 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): Virgil Williams / 1880. University of California label (78-10-06381) on verso.
      Three children at play on stairway in walled city; stepped, white adobe buildings, doorways, and walkways rise in distance.
    - San Antonio Mission, [ca. 1875 - ca.1885]; Young, John F.; BANC PIC 19xx.500:030--FR; 1 painting: oil; 41.4 x 51.4 cm. Handwritten label (verso) San Antonio Mission / painted by John F. Young / in late 70's early 80's.
      View of San Antonio de Padua (Mission) buildings showing western façade and open colonnade.